<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Unity</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <string name="images">image</string>


    // Earthquake


    <string name="aearthq_h">-: Earthquake :-</string>

    <string name="aearthq_t1">\n
        \nEarthquakes are a sudden slipping or movement of a portion of the earth’s crust, accompanied or followed by a
        series of vibrations. Earthquakes strike suddenly, violently, without warning. Earthquakes occurring in a
        populated area may cause many deaths, injuries and extensive damage to property.
        \n\nTherefore, every citizen should be aware of risks and be better prepared to respond in case of a major
        earthquake.
        \n\nWe should ask ourselves the following questions:
        \n\n• Why do earthquakes happen?
        \n\n• How can we protect ourselves?
        \n\n• What must we do to minimize the damage?
        \n\n Earthquakes cannot be predicted but we can be proactive. Earthquake protection is about a whole series of
        measures, small and big, that you can and must work on today to ensure that tomorrow is safe. The truth is
        “Earthquake do not kill, unsafe buildings do!” Loss of human lives and injuries are caused due to collapse of
        buildings. Poor design, poor construction, and poor maintenance - these are the killers.
    </string>

    <string name="aearthq_t2">
        \n\nBefore an Earthquake
        \n\nBefore an earthquake you can take some non structural mitigation measures to reduce risks, like those given
        below:
        \n\n• Make sure you have a fire extinguisher, first aid kit, a battery-powered radio, a flashlight, and extra
        batteries at home.
        \n\n• Learn first aid.
        \n\n• Learn how to turn off the gas, water, and electricity.
        \n\n• Make up a plan of where to meet your family after an earthquake.
        \n\n• Don\'t leave heavy objects on shelves (they\'ll fall during a quake).
        \n\n• Anchor heavy furniture, cupboards, and appliances to the walls or floor.
        \n\n• Learn the earthquake plan at your school or workplace
        \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="aearthq_t3">
        \n\nDuring an Earthquake
        \n\n
        \n\n• Stay calm! If you\'re indoors, stay inside. If you\'re outside, stay outside.
        \n\n• If you\'re indoors, stand against a wall near the center of the building, stand in a doorway, or crawl
        under heavy furniture (a desk or table). Stay away from windows and outside doors.
        \n\n• If you\'re outdoors, stay in the open away from power lines or anything that might fall. Stay away from
        buildings (stuff might fall off the building or the building could fall on you).
        \n\n• Don\'t use matches, candles, or any flame. Broken gas lines and fire don\'t mix.
        \n\n• If you\'re in a car, stop the car and stay inside the car until the earthquake stops.
        \n\n• Don\'t use elevators (they\'ll probably get stuck anyway).
        \n\n
    </string>/

    <string name="aearthq_t4">
        \n\nAfter an Earthquake
        \n\n
        \n\n• Check yourself and others for injuries. Provide first aid for anyone who needs it.
        \n\n• Check water, gas, and electric lines for damage. If any are damaged, shut off the valves. Check for the
        smell of gas. If you smell it, open all the windows and doors, leave immediately, and report it to the
        authorities (use someone else\'s phone).
        \n\n• Turn on the radio. Don\'t use the phone unless it\'s an emergency.
        \n\n• Stay out of damaged buildings.
        \n\n• Be careful around broken glass and debris. Wear boots or sturdy shoes to keep from cutting your feet.
        \n\n• Be careful of chimneys (they may fall on you).
        \n\n• Stay away from beaches. Tsunamis and seiches sometimes hit after the ground has stopped shaking.
        \n\n• Stay away from damaged areas.
        \n\n• If you\'re at school or work, follow the emergency plan or the instructions of the person in charge.
        \n\nIf you are trapped under debris/rubble:
        \n\n• Do not panic protect your head and face from falling objects.
        \n\n• Crawl under a sturdy table, desk or bed as that will provide air space and protect against falling
        objects.
        \n\n• Use a torch to attract attention
        \n\n• Do not use matches and candle if there is a danger of gas leak
        \n\n• Do not shout
        \n\nIf you are trapped under debris/rubble:
        \n\n• Do not panic protect your head and face from falling objects.
        \n\n• Crawl under a sturdy table, desk or bed as that will provide air space and protect against falling
        objects.
        \n\n• Use a torch to attract attention
        \n\n• Do not use matches and candle if there is a danger of gas leak
        \n\n• Do not shout,if you are in damaged area by sound vibration it may collapse.

    </string>


    // Floods


    <string name="aflood_h">-: Floods :-</string>
    <string name="aflood_t1">\n

        Floods are natural occurrences where an area or land that is normally dry abruptly becomes submerged in water.
        In simple terms, flood can be defined as an overflow of large quantities of water onto a normally dry land.
        Flooding happens in many ways due to overflow of streams, rivers, lakes or oceans or as a result of excessive
        rain.
        \n\nWhenever flooding takes place, there is the possibility of loss of life, hardship to people, and extensive
        damage to property. This is because flooding can carry bridges, cars, houses, and even people. Flooding also
        destroys crops and can wipe away trees and other important structures on land. Some floods occur abruptly and
        recede quickly whereas others take several days or even months to form and to recede because of variation in
        size, duration, and the area affected.
        \n\nCauses of Flooding
        \n\nMany conditions result in flooding. Hurricanes, clogged drainages, and rainfall are some of the conditions
        that have led to flooding in various regions across the globe. Here are the leading causes of flooding.
        \n\n1. Rain
        \n\nRain is the leading contributor to most of the flooding cases witnessed across the world. Too much rain
        causes water to flow overland contributing to flooding. In particular, it is due to high rainfall intensity over
        a prolonged period.
        \n\nDepending on the rainfall distribution, the amount of rain, and soil moisture content, short rainfall period
        can also result in flooding. Light rains for longer periods – several days or weeks, can also result in floods.
        The rain water erosive force can weaken the foundations of buildings, causing tumbles and cracks.
        \n\n2. River Overflows
        \n\nRivers or streams can overflow their banks. This happens when the river or stream holds more water upstream
        than usual, and it flows downstream to the neighboring low-lying areas, typically referred to as the
        floodplains. As a consequence, this creates a sudden discharge of water into the adjacent lands leading to
        flooding.
        \n\nDams in rivers may also at times overwhelm rivers when the carriage capacity is exceeded, causing the water
        to burst and get into the floodplains. Flood caused by river overflow has the potential of sweeping everything
        in its path downstream.
        \n\n3. Lakes and Coastal Flooding
        \n\nLake and Coastal flooding occurs when large storms or tsunamis causes the water body to surge inland. These
        overflows have destructive power since they can destroy ill-equipped structures to withstand water’s strength
        such as bridges, houses, and cars.
        \n\nIn the coastal areas, strong and massive winds and hurricanes drive water onto the dry coastal lands and
        give rise to flooding. The situation is even worsened when the winds blowing from the ocean carry rains in them.
        Sea waters from the tsunami or hurricane can cause widespread damage.
        \n\n4. Dam Breakage
        \n\nDams are man-made structures used to hold water from flowing down from a raised ground. The potential energy
        stored in the dam water is used to generate electricity. At times, the walls can become weak and break because
        of overwhelming carriage capacity. Due to this reason, breakage of the dam can cause extensive flooding in the
        adjacent areas.
        \n\nFlooding occurs when the embankments built along the sides of the river to stop high water from flowing onto
        the land breaks. Sometimes, the excess water from the dam is deliberately released from the dam to prevent it
        from breaking thereby causing floods.
        \n\n5. Melting of the Glaciers and Mountain Tops
        \n\nIn the cold regions, ice and snows build up during the winters. When the temperature rises in summer, the
        accumulated snows and ice are subjected to melting resulting in vast movements of water into lands that are
        normally dry. Regions with mountains that have ice on top of them also experience the same outcome when the
        atmospheric temperature rises. This type of flooding is usually termed as snowmelt flood.
        \n\n6. Clogged Drainages
        \n\nFlooding also takes place when snowmelt or rainfall runoff cannot be channeled appropriately into the
        drainage systems forcing the water to flow overland. Clogged or lack of proper drainage system is usually the
        cause of this type of flooding.
        \n\nThe areas remain flooded until the stormwater systems or waterways are rectified. Instances where the
        systems or water ways are not rectified, the areas remain flooded until the excess water evaporates or is
        transpired into the atmosphere by plants.


    </string>

    // #### House Fire
    <string name="ahousefire_h">-: Wild Fire :-</string>
    <string name="ahousefire_t1">\n
        \n\nIn just two minutes, a fire can become life-threatening. In five minutes, a residence can be engulfed in
        flames.
        \n\nLearn About Fires
        \n\n
        \n\n Fire is FAST! In less than 30 seconds a small flame can turn into a major fire. It only takes minutes for
        thick black smoke to fill a house or for it to be engulfed in flames.
        \n\n Fire is HOT! Heat is more threatening than flames. Room temperatures in a fire can be 100 degrees at floor
        level and rise to 600 degrees at eye level. Inhaling this super-hot air will scorch your lungs and melt clothes
        to your skin.
        \n\n Fire is DARK! Fire starts bright, but quickly produces black smoke and complete darkness.
        \n\n Fire is DEADLY! Smoke and toxic gases kill more people than flames do. Fire produces poisonous gases that
        make you disoriented and drowsy. Asphyxiation is the leading cause of fire deaths, exceeding burns by a
        three-to-one ratio.
        \n\n
    </string>


    // ### Landslide


    <string name="landside_h">-: Landslides :-</string>
    <string name="landslide_t1">
        \n\nA landslide happens when rocks, debris, and soil move down a slope. They\'re also known as landslips. Things
        can go downhill suddenly, or they can slide at the snail\'s pace of just a couple centimeters a year. They can
        come from natural causes or from the activities of people. The one thing they all have in common is gravity.
        What is up sometimes slides down.
        \n\n
        \n\n Causes of Landslides
        \n\n
        \n\nThe cause of a landslide that has to do with the structural combination of rock, soil and vegetation is the
        morphology. If a hillside has lost vegetation because of a fire for instance, then the addition of water can
        cause erosion, upping the chances for a landslide. It\'s not only rain that can cause erosion but flowing
        rivers, moving glaciers, and crashing ocean waves. The geology or strength of the earth material itself can also
        be a factor in landslides. Stronger material is less likely to break apart and slide down the slope. And
        finally, there are human activities that can expose slopes to erosion and lead to landslides. Clearing land for
        agriculture or construction are some of the human causes of landslides.
        \n\n
    </string>

    // First Aid

    // ###### Burns


    <string name="burns_h">-: Burns :-</string>


    <string name="burns_t1">
        \n1. Halt the burning process to stop the injury. \n\n
        Even if you are no longer in contact with the cause of the burn (such as an open flame or the sun), tissue
        damage can continue. Thus, it is essential you reduce further damage first before attempting to clean the
        injured area \n\n
        • Place the affected part under cool running water for approximately 15-20 minutes.\n\n
        • If the burn is on your face, hands, over a joint, or is large, seek medical attention right away.\n\n
        • Use warm water for less harsh chemicals or when there is chemical exposure to the eyes.\n\n
        • It is also important that you call your doctor if you have a chemical exposure to your eyes or mouth as this
        can cause more serious complications.\n\n
        • In the case of a chemical burn, you must neutralize the burning chemical. If you are unsure how to do this,
        seek medical attention.\n\n
        • If you are not near water, apply a cool compress to the area such as an ice pack wrapped in a towel.\n\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="burns_t2">\n
        2. Apply lotion to the burn.\n\n
        Use aloe vera lotion or gel or a low-dose hydrocortisone cream to protect the skin and help the healing
        process\n\n
        • Be sure to pat dry the skin before applying any lotion if needed.\n\n
        • Reapply the aloe vera lotion throughout the day to ensure the affected area remains moist, but don\'t use
        hydrocortisone cream more than twice a day.\n\n


    </string>

    <string name="burns_t3">\n
        3. Take over-the-counter pain reliever if the burn is causing pain. Burn injuries can be painful and thus you
        may want to take an over-the-counter pain medication (such as acetaminophen or ibuprofen). \n\n
        • Use the medication according to the label and do not exceed the recommended dose. In case of severe or
        continuing pain, seek medical attention.\n\n


    </string>

    <string name="burns_t4">\n
        4. Try to keep blisters intact. Burn injuries often result in blisters — fluid-filled pockets under your skin.
        \n\n• If the blister breaks, rinse the area with water, apply antimicrobial ointment and cover the area with a
        non-stick bandage.


    </string>

    <string name="burns_t5">\n
        5. Watch the area for signs of infection. If redness, tenderness, swelling or drainage develops, apply
        antimicrobial ointment and cover the burn with clean gauze to protect it while it heals.
        \n\n• Contact a physician if the burn gets worse, does not appear to ease, it looks infected and is not getting
        better quickly with home care, or develops severe blisters or discoloration of any kind.
    </string>


    // ###### Cuts


    <string name="cuts_h">-: Cuts/Bandages :-</string>
    <string name="cuts_t1">\n

        1. Wash your hands. This helps avoid infection.\n\n
        2. Stop the bleeding. Minor cuts and scrapes usually stop bleeding on their own. If needed, apply gentle
        pressure with a clean bandage or cloth and elevate the wound until bleeding stops.\n\n
        3. Clean the wound. Rinse the wound with water. Keeping the wound under running tap water will reduce the risk
        of infection. Wash around the wound with soap. But don\'t get soap in the wound. And don\'t use hydrogen
        peroxide or iodine, which can be irritating. Remove any dirt or debris with a tweezers cleaned with alcohol. See
        a doctor if you can\'t remove all debris.\n\n
        4. Apply an antibiotic or petroleum jelly. Apply a thin layer of an antibiotic ointment or petroleum jelly to
        keep the surface moist and help prevent scarring. Certain ingredients in some ointments can cause a mild rash in
        some people. If a rash appears, stop using the ointment.\n\n
        5. Cover the wound. Apply a bandage, rolled gauze or gauze held in place with paper tape. Covering the wound
        keeps it clean. If the injury is just a minor scrape or scratch, leave it uncovered.\n\n
        6. Change the dressing. Do this at least once a day or whenever the bandage becomes wet or dirty.\n\n
        7. Get a tetanus shot. Get a tetanus shot if you haven\'t had one in the past five years and the wound is deep
        or dirty.\n\n
        8. Watch for signs of infection. See a doctor if you see signs of infection on the skin or near the wound, such
        as redness, increasing pain, drainage, warmth or swelling.\n\n

    </string>
    // ##### Fractures

    <string name="fractures_h">-: Fractures :-</string>
    <string name="fractures_t1">\n

        \n\n
        1.
        \n\nAssess the injured area. In an emergency situation with no trained medical people around, you need to
        quickly assess the seriousness of the injury. Trauma from a fall or accident coupled with severe pain is not a
        guarantee of a broken bone, but it\'s usually a pretty good indicator. Fractures involving the head, spine or
        pelvis are difficult to tell without an x-ray, but you suspect a break in one of these areas you should not
        attempt to move the person. Bones in the arms, legs, fingers, and toes will typically look crooked, misshapen or
        obviously out of place when broken. A severely broken bone might poke out through the skin (open fracture) and
        involve profuse bleeding.
        \n\no Other common symptoms of broken bones include: limited use of the injured area (reduced mobility or unable
        to put any weight on it), immediate local swelling and bruising, numbness or tingling downstream from the break,
        shortness of breath, nausea.
        \n\no Be very careful when assessing the injury not to cause much movement. Moving a person with an injured
        spine, neck, pelvis or skull is very risky without medical training and should be avoided.
        \n\n

        \n\n2.
        \n\nCall for emergency help if the injury is severe. Once you\'ve established that the injury is serious and
        suspect that a broken bone is likely, then call 1-0-2 for an ambulance and get professional medical help on
        their way as quickly as you can. Providing immediate rudimentary first aid and supportive care are certainly
        helpful, but it\'s no substitute for trained medical attention. If you are close to a hospital or emergency
        clinic and are quite certain the injury is not life threatening and only involves a limb, then consider driving
        the injured person to the facility.
        \n\no Even if you think your fracture is not life threatening, resist the urge to drive yourself to the
        hospital. You may not be able to operate your vehicle properly or may lose consciousness from the pain and
        become a road hazard.
        \n\no If the injury appears severe, stay on the line with the 1-0-2 dispatcher in case conditions get worse in
        order to get helpful instructions and emotional support.
        \n\no Call emergency services if you notice the following: call for emergency help if The person is
        unresponsive, isn\'t breathing, or isn\'t moving; there is heavy bleeding; gentle pressure or movement causes
        pain; the limb or joint appears deformed; the bone has pierced the skin; the extremity of the injured arm or
        leg, such as a toe or finger, is numb or bluish at the tip; you suspect a bone is broken in the neck, head or
        back.
        \n\n

        \n\n3.
        \n\nProvide CPR if necessary. If the injured person is not breathing and you can\'t feel a pulse on her wrists
        or neck, then start administering cardiopulmonary resuscitation (if you know how to) before the ambulance
        arrives. CPR involves clearing the airways, blowing air into the mouth / lungs and trying to restart the heart
        by rhythmically pushing on the chest.
        \n\no A lack of oxygen for much more than five to seven minutes causes, at least, some degree of brain damage,
        so time is of the essence.
        \n\no If you\'re not trained in CPR, then provide hands-only CPR — uninterrupted chest compressions at a rate of
        about 100 per minute until paramedics arrive.
        \n\no If you\'re well-trained in CPR, begin with chest compressions immediately (about 20 – 30) and then check
        the airway for obstruction and start doing rescue breathing after tilting the head back at a slight angle.
        \n\no For a spine, neck, or skull injury, do not use the head-tilt-chin-lift method. Use the jaw-thrust method
        of airway opening, but only if you have been trained how to do so. The jaw-thrust method involves kneeling
        behind the person and placing a hand on either side of her face, middle and index fingers beneath and behind the
        jaw. Push each side of the jaw forward until it juts out.

        \n\n4.
        \n\nStop any bleeding. If the injury is bleeding significantly (more than a few drops), then you must attempt to
        stop it regardless if there is a fracture or not. Significant bleeding from the main artery can lead to death
        within a few minutes. Controlling the bleeding is a higher priority than addressing a broken bone. Apply firm
        pressure to the wound with a sterile and absorbent bandage (ideally), although a clean towel or piece of
        clothing will do in an emergency.Hold it there for a few minutes to encourage the blood to clot at the injury
        site. Secure the bandage around the wound with an elastic bandage or piece of cloth if you can.
        \n\no If the bleeding won\'t stop from an injured limb, you may have to tie a tight tourniquet above the wound
        to temporarily cut off the circulation until medical help arrives. A tourniquet can be made of virtually
        anything that can be secured tight — string, rope, cord, rubber tubing, leather belt, necktie, scarf, tee-shirt,
        etc.
        \n\no If there is a large object penetrating into the skin, do not remove it. It may be clotting the wound, and
        removing it could cause severe bleeding.
        \n\n
        \n\n


    </string>


    <string name="fractures_t2">

        \n\nAddressing the Broken Bone
        \n\n
        1.
        \n\nImmobilize the broken bone. After the injured person is stabilized, it\'s time to immobilize the broken bone
        if you anticipate a wait of an hour or longer for emergency medical personnel. Immobilizing it can help reduce
        the pain and protect the broken bone from further injury caused by inadvertent movement. If you don\'t have
        proper training, don\'t try to realign the bone. Attempting to align broken bones improperly can lead to further
        damage to blood vessels and nerves, leading to potential bleeding and potential paralysis. Keep in mind that
        splints only work for limb bones, not those of the pelvis or torso.
        \n\no The best method of immobilization is to make a simple splint. Place a piece of stiff cardboard or plastic,
        a branch or stick, a metal rod, or rolled up newspaper/magazine on either side of the injury to support the
        bone. Tie these supports together firmly with tape, string, rope, cord, rubber tubing, leather belt, necktie,
        scarf, etc.
        \n\no When splinting a fractured bone, try to allow movement in the adjacent joints and don\'t secure it too
        tight — allow appropriate blood circulation.
        \n\no Splinting may not be necessary if emergency services are coming right away. In this case, splinting may
        cause more harm than good if you don\'t have the appropriate training.
        \n\n
        2.
        \n\nApply ice to the injury. Once the broken bone is immobilized, apply something cold (preferably ice) to it as
        soon as you can while you wait for the ambulance. Cold therapy has many benefits, including numbing the pain,
        reducing inflammation / swelling and reducing bleeding by causing the arteries to constrict. If you don\'t have
        ice handy, consider using frozen gel packs or bags of vegetables, but make sure to wrap anything cold in a thin
        cloth in order to avoid ice burn or frostbite.
        \n\no Apply ice for about 20 minutes or until the area is completely numb before removing it. Compressing it
        against the injury may help reduce swelling even more as long as it doesn\'t increase the pain.
        \n\no While applying the ice, make sure the broken bone is elevated in order to combat swelling and slow down
        bleeding (if applicable).
        \n\n
        3.
        \n\nKeep calm and watch for signs of shock. Breaking a bone is very traumatic and painful. Fear, panic, and
        shock are all common reactions, but they can have negative consequences for the body, so they must be
        controlled. As such, calm yourself and/or the injured person by reassuring him that help is on the way and the
        situation is under control. As you wait for help, cover the person to keep him warm and hydrate him if they are
        thirsty. Keep talking to him to distract him from focusing on his injury.
        \n\no Signs of shock include: feeling faint / dizzy, pale complexion, cold sweats, rapid breathing, increased
        heart rate, confusion, irrational panic.
        \n\no If it looks like the person is in shock, lay him down with his head supported and elevate his legs. Keep
        him covered with a blanket or jacket, or even a table cloth if those things are not available.
        \n\no Shock is dangerous because blood and oxygen are routed away from vital organs. This physiological state,
        if left untreated, can ultimately cause organ damage.
        \n\n
        4.
        \n\nConsider pain medication. If the wait for emergency medical personnel is longer than an hour (or you
        anticipate it being a long wait), then consider taking / giving some medication, if you have any, to control the
        pain and make the wait more tolerable. Acetaminophen (Tylenol) is the painkiller most appropriate for broken
        bones and other internal injuries because it doesn\'t "thin" the blood and promote more bleeding.
        \n\no Over-the-counter anti-inflammatories such as aspirin and ibuprofen (Advil) are helpful for pain and
        inflammation, but they inhibit blood clotting, so they aren\'t a good idea for internal injuries such as broken
        bones.
        \n\no In addition, aspirin and ibuprofen should not be given to young children, because they may cause dangerous
        side effects.


    </string>
    // #### Punchers
    <string name="punchers_h">-: Punchers :-</string>
    <string name="punchers_t1">\n

        \n\n
        \n\n1 .Wash your hands before attempting to care for the wound. Use warm water and soap and rinse at least for
        30 seconds to ensure your hands are clean.
        \n\n• Also, dry your hands well before touching the affected area to reduce the risk of infection.
        \n\n

        \n\n2 .Rinse the affected area with clean water to remove dirt and debris. If washing does not remove all
        debris, use tweezers cleaned with alcohol to remove the particles. Also, remove the object that caused the
        puncture if still present.
        \n\n• If the object that caused the puncture is still inside your skin and cannot be removed completely, or if
        you cannot remove the object without causing further damage, seek medical attention.
        \n\n
        \n\n
        \n\n3 .Apply pressure with a clean cloth to stop bleeding. If bleeding occurs, apply pressure to stop it. You
        can use a clean cloth to press the injury or, if available, an ice pack wrapped in a towel.
        \n\n• Depending on the type and size of the injury, the puncture might not be bleeding at all.
        \n\n
        \n\n

        \n\n4 .Apply a thin layer of antimicrobial ointment over the area. Do this ONLY for superficial wounds. If the
        wound is large, open and affects deep tissues, do not apply any topical medication and seek medical attention.


        \n\n
        \n\n5 .Cover the wound with a clean dressing or a bandage. This will help keep the wound clean and reduces the
        risk of infection and other complications.
        \n\n• Change the bandage a few times a day and every time it gets wet or dirty.
        \n\n• Consult your doctor whether you should receive a tetanus booster shot within 48 hours. This is usually
        recommended if it\'s been more than 5 years since you\'ve had a tetanus shot. Even minor puncture wounds can
        lead to infection.


        \n\n
        \n\n6 .Watch the area for signs of infection (redness, pain, pus or swelling). If the wound is not healing or
        you notice excessive pain, warmth, redness and/or drainage, seek medical attention immediately.
        \n\n

    </string>

    // ##### Snake Bites


    <string name="sb_h">-: Snake Bites :-</string>
    <string name="sb_t1">\n

        \n\nWhile many snakes are harmless, the bite of some species can be poisonous and even deadly. Common species of
        poisonous snakes:
        \n\n• copperhead
        \n\n• coral
        \n\n• cottonmouth
        \n\n• rattlesnake
        \n\nSymptoms of a poisonous snake bite can vary, depending on the type of snake. They can include:
        \n\n• weakness
        \n\n• dizziness
        \n\n• fainting
        \n\n• convulsions
        \n\n• nausea
        \n\n• vomiting
        \n\n• diarrhea
        \n\n• rapid pulse
        \n\n• loss of muscle coordination
        \n\n• swelling in the area of the bite
        \n\n\n\n
        A poisonous snake bite is a medical emergency. Prompt treatment can minimize symptoms and promote recovery.
        \n\n

    </string>

    <string name="sb_t2">\n

        \n\nFirst aid treatment for mild bites\n\n
        \n\nIf someone has been bitten by a snake, and you suspect it may be poisonous, help them get emergency medical
        treatment and follow the steps in the next session. If you know the snake wasn’t poisonous, treat the area of
        the bite for bleeding and other symptoms:
        \n\n• Use a clean cloth or gauze to apply pressure to the area until bleeding stops.
        \n\n• Clean the area with soap and water.
        \n\n• Apply an antibiotic cream to help ward off infection.
        \n\n• Cover the wound with a sterile bandage or gauze to protect it while it heals.
        \n\nIf the person is experiencing severe bleeding, help them get emergency medical treatment. Continue to apply
        new layers of cloth or gauze to the bleeding area, on top of layers that have been soaked through with blood.
        Removing old layers can make the bleeding worse.
        \n\nEmergency treatment for poisonous snake bites
        \n\nIf you suspect that someone has been bitten by a poisonous snake:
        \n\n• Help them get medical help immediately. You can also call 102
        \n\n• Encourage them to remain calm, lie down quietly, and stay still. Movement can cause the venom to spread
        through their body more quickly.
        \n\n• Remove tight jewelry or clothing around the site of the bite, since swelling may occur.
        \n\n• If they develop pale and clammy skin, dizziness, weakness, shortness of breath, or increased heart rate,
        treat them for shock. Give them a blanket or extra layer of clothing to stay warm.
        \n\n• If you can do so safely, take a description or picture of the snake that bit them. This can help medical
        professionals identify the snake and an appropriate course of treatment.
        \n\nTo avoid making things worse, do not:
        \n\n• endanger yourself by trying to capture the snake
        \n\n• wash the site of the bite, since residual venom can help medical professionals identify the type of snake
        and proper treatment
        \n\n• apply a cold compress to the site of the bite
        \n\n• raise the bitten area above the level of their heart
        \n\n• cut or suck the site of the bite
        \n\n• give the person anything to eat or drink
        \n\n• give the person any pain medications
        \n\n

    </string>

    // ##### Food


    <string name="sfood_h">-: Food :-</string>
    <string name="sfood_t1">Following a disaster, there may be power outages that could last for several days. Stock
        canned foods, dry
        mixes and other staples that do not require refrigeration, cooking, water or special preparation. Be sure to
        include a manual can opener and eating utensils.
        \n\nSuggested Emergency Food Supplies
        \n\nConsider the following things when putting together your emergency food supplies:
        \n\n• Store at least a three-day supply of non-perishable food.
        \n\n• Choose foods your family will eat.
        \n\n• Remember any special dietary needs.
        \n\n• Avoid foods that will make you thirsty.
        \n\nThe following items are suggested when selecting emergency food supplies. You may already have many of these
        on hand. Download the Recommended Supplies List (PDF)
        \n\n• Ready-to-eat canned meats, fruits, vegetables and a can opener
        \n\n• Protein or fruit bars
        \n\n• Dry cereal or granola
        \n\n• Peanut butter
        \n\n• Dried fruit
        \n\n• Canned juices
        \n\n• Non-perishable pasteurized milk
        \n\n• High energy foods
        \n\n• Food for infants
        \n\n• Comfort/stress foods
        \n\nFood Safety and Sanitation
        \n\nWithout electricity or a cold source, food stored in refrigerators and freezers can become unsafe. Bacteria
        in food grow rapidly at temperatures between 40 and 140 °F, and if these foods are consumed you can become very
        sick. Thawed food usually can be eaten if it is still “refrigerator cold.” It can be re-frozen if it still
        contains ice crystals. To be safe, remember, “When in doubt, throw it out.”
        \n\nDo:
        \n\n• Keep food in covered containers.
        \n\n• Keep cooking and eating utensils clean.
        \n\n• Discard any food that has come into contact with contaminated flood water.
        \n\n• Discard any food that has been at room temperature for two hours or more.
        \n\n• Discard any food that has an unusual odor, color or texture.
        \n\n• Use ready-to-feed formula. If you must mix infant formula use bottled water, or boiled as a last resort.
        \n\nDon’t:
        \n\n• Eat foods from cans that are swollen, dented or corroded, even though the product may look safe to eat.
        \n\n• Eat any food that looks or smells abnormal, even if the can looks normal.
        \n\n• Let garbage accumulate inside, both for fire and sanitation reasons.
        \n\nCooking
        \n\nAlternative cooking sources can be used in times of emergency including candle warmers, chafing dishes,
        fondue pots or a fireplace. Charcoal grills and camp stoves are for outdoor use only. Commercially canned food
        may be eaten out of the can without warming.
        \n\nTo heat food in a can:
        \n\n1. Remove the label.
        \n\n2. Thoroughly wash and disinfect the can. (Use a diluted solution of one part bleach to ten parts water.)
        \n\n3. Open the can before heating.
        \n\nManaging Food without Power
        \n\n• Keep the refrigerator and freezer doors closed as much as possible.
        \n\n• The refrigerator will keep food cold for about 4 hours if it is unopened.
        \n\n• Refrigerated or frozen foods should be kept at 40° F or below for proper food storage.
        \n\n• Use a refrigerator thermometer to check temperature.
        \n\n• Refrigerated food should be safe as long as the power was out for no more than 4 hours.
        \n\n• Discard any perishable food (such as meat, poultry, fish, eggs or leftovers) that has been above 40° F for
        two hours or more.
        \n\nUsing Dry Ice:
        \n\n• Know where you can get dry ice prior to a power outage.
        \n\n• Twenty-five pounds of dry ice will keep a 10-cubic-foot freezer below freezing for 3-4 days.
        \n\n• If you use dry ice to keep your food cold, make sure it does not come in direct contact with the food.
        \n\n• Use care when handling dry ice, wear dry, heavy gloves to avoid injury.
        \n\n


    </string>

    // ##### Landslides


    <string name="sur_landside_h">-: Landslides :-</string>
    <string name="sur_landslide_t1">\n
        \n\n
        \n\nBefore a landslide :
        \n\nBe aware of your environment. If you travel or are on vacation somewhere, look around and make sure you
        understand where the threat may be. Look out for slopes and tricky landscapes. Contact your local authorities
        and tell them about your observations.
        \n\n
        \n\nWhen you drive around hills or mountains, keep your eyes and ears open for signs of debris falling. Plan
        communications with your family so that you know where they are and what you will do in an event of a landslide.
        Have an emergency kit in a safe and reliable place. Talk to neighbors and discuss an escape plan. If possible,
        evacuate before it happens.
        \n\n
        \n\nDuring a landslide:
        \n\nLandslides and mudslides happen very fast and there may be very little time to act. Move away quickly from
        the path of the mudflow or landslide to another location. Do not try to stay close and take photographs.
        Landslide debris move from uphill to downhill, therefore, avoid low-lying areas or valleys. If there is a way to
        sound an alarm, do so.
        \n\nListen and look out for signs of further flows in that area, as the flowing debris often knock against
        surrounding slopes and sets off new flows.
        \n\n
        \n\nAfter a landslide:
        \n\nStay away from the location until the emergency workers and the experts confirm that it is safe to go back.
        Look out for loose wires, broken utility lines, and hanging objects, as they may be hazards. Report them to your
        rescue officials. Get in touch with emergency officials or listen to the radio or TV on what to do.
        \n\n
    </string>

    // ##### Floods


    <string name="sflood_h">-: Floods :-</string>
    <string name="sflood_t1">\n


        \n\n
        BEFORE A FLOOD (When Flooding is Forecast)\n\n
        Be alert.\n\n
        • Monitor your surroundings.\n\n
        • Monitor Weather by local television and radio stations.\n\n
        If a flash flood warning is issued for your area: Climb to safety immediately.\n\n
        • Flash floods develop quickly. Do not wait until you see rising water.\n\n
        • Get out of low areas subject to flooding.\n\n
        • If driving, do not drive through flooded roadways!\n\n
        Assemble disaster supplies:\n\n
        • Drinking water – Fill clean containers.\n\n
        • Food that requires no refrigeration or cooking.\n\n
        • Cash.\n\n
        • Medications and first aid supplies.\n\n
        • Clothing, toiletries.\n\n
        • Battery-powered radio.\n\n
        • Flashlights.\n\n
        • Extra batteries.\n\n
        • Important documents: insurance papers, medical records, bank account numbers.\n\n\n\n
        Be prepared to evacuate.\n\n
        • Identify places to go.\n\n
        • Identify alternative travel routes that are not prone to flooding.\n\n
        • Plan what to do with your pets.\n\n
        • Fill your car’s gas tank.\n\n
        • If told to leave, do so quickly.\n\n
        Review your Family Disaster Plan.\n\n
        • Discuss flood plans with your family.\n\n
        • Decide where you will meet if separated.\n\n
        • Designate a contact person who can be reached if family members get separated. Make sure every family member
        has the contact information.\n\n
        Protect your property.\n\n
        • Move valuables and furniture to higher levels.\n\n
        • Move hazardous materials (such as paint, oil, pesticides, and cleaning supplies) to higher locations.\n\n
        • Disconnect electrical appliances. Do not touch them if you are wet or standing in water.\n\n
        • Bring outside possessions indoors or tie them down securely. This includes lawn furniture, garbage cans, and
        other movable objects.\n\n
        • Seal vents to basements to prevent flooding.\n\n\n\n


    </string>

    <string name="sflood_t2">\n
        \n\nDURING A FLOOD\n\n
        Be alert.\n\n
        • Monitor your surroundings.\n\n
        • Monitor by local television and radio stations, or go to \n\n
        Don’t drive unless you have to.\n\n
        If you must drive, travel with care.\n\n
        • Make sure your vehicle has enough fuel.\n\n
        • Follow recommended routes. DO NOT sightsee.\n\n
        • Avoid disaster areas. Your presence might hamper rescue or other emergency operations and put you at further
        risk.\n\n
        • Watch for washed out roads, earth slides, and downed trees or power lines.\n\n
        • Be especially cautious at night, when it is harder to recognize flood dangers.\n\n
        • If the vehicle stalls, abandon it.\n\n
        • If water rises around your car, leave the vehicle immediately. Climb to higher ground as quickly as
        possible.\n\n
        NEVER drive through flooded roadways. STOP! Turn Around Don’t Drown.\n\n
        • The roadbed may be washed out.\n\n
        • You can lose control of your vehicle in only a few inches of water.\n\n
        • Your car may float. Vehicles can be swept away by less than 2 feet of water.\n\n
        • Do not drive around a barricade. Turn around and go another way!\n\n
        Get to high ground – Climb to safety!\n\n
        • Get out of low areas that may be subject to flooding.\n\n
        • Avoid already-flooded areas and do not attempt to cross flowing water.\n\n
        • Stay away from power lines and electrical wires.\n\n
        Evacuate immediately, if you think you are at risk or are advised to do so!\n\n
        • Act quickly. Save yourself, not your belongings.\n\n
        • Move to a safe area before access is cut off by rising water.\n\n
        • Families should use only one vehicle to avoid getting separated and reduce traffic jams.\n\n
        • Shut off water, gas, and electrical services before leaving.\n\n
        • Secure your home: lock all doors and windows.\n\n
        • If directed to a specific location, go there.\n\n
        Never try to walk or swim through flowing water.\n\n
        • If flowing water is above your ankles, STOP! Turn around and go another way.\n\n
        • If it is moving swiftly, water 6 inches deep can knock you off your feet.\n\n
        • Be aware that people have been swept away wading through flood waters.\n\n
        • NEVER allow children to play around high water, storm drains, creeks, or rivers.\n\n
        Shut off the electricity at the circuit breakers.\n\n
        If someone falls in or is trapped in flood water:\n\n
        • Do not go after the victim!\n\n
        • Use a floatation device. If possible throw the victim something to help them float, such as a spare tire,
        large ball, or foam ice chest.\n\n
        • Call 108. Call for assistance and give the correct location information.\n\n

    </string>


    <string name="sflood_t3">\n

        \n\nAFTER A FLOOD\n\n
        Wait until it is safe to return.\n\n
        • Monitor NOAA Weather Radio or local television and radio stations.\n\n
        • Do not return to flooded areas until authorities indicate it is safe to do so.\n\n
        • Do not visit disaster areas following a flood. Your presence may hamper urgent emergency response and rescue
        operations.\n\n
        Travel with care. \n\n
        • Follow recommended routes. DO NOT sightsee.\n\n
        • Watch for washed out roads, earth slides, and downed trees or power lines.\n\n
        • Stay away from downed power lines.\n\n
        If a building was flooded, check for safety before entering.\n\n
        • Do not enter a building if it is still flooded or surrounded by floodwater.\n\n
        • Check for structural damage. Inspect foundations for cracks or other damage.\n\n
        • Turn off any outside gas lines at the meter tank.\n\n
        • Do not enter a building that has flooded until local building officials have inspected it for safety.\n\n
        Use extreme caution when entering buildings.\n\n
        • Wear sturdy shoes. The most common injury following a disaster is cut feet.\n\n
        • Use ONLY battery-powered lighting. Flammable material may be present.\n\n
        • Look for fire hazards (such as damaged gas lines, flooded electrical circuits, or submerged furnaces).\n\n
        • Check for gas leaks. If you smell gas or hear a blowing or hissing noise, open a window and quickly leave the
        building. If possible turn off the gas at the outside main valve. Call the gas company.\n\n
        • Report broken utility lines to appropriate authorities.\n\n
        • Check for electrical system damage (sparks, broken or frayed wires, or the smell of burning insulation). Turn
        off the electricity at the main circuit breaker if you can reach it without stepping in water.\n\n
        • Examine walls, floors, doors, windows, and ceilings for risk of collapsing.\n\n
        • Watch out for animals that might have entered with the floodwaters.\n\n
        • Let the building air out to remove foul odors or escaping gas. \n\n
        Take pictures of the damage, both of the building and its contents, for insurance claims.\n\n
        Get professional help.\n\n
        • Seek necessary medical care. Do not neglect minor wounds or illnesses.\n\n
        • Food, clothing, shelter, and first aid are available from the American Red Cross.\n\n
        • If the gas has been turned off for any reason, it must be turned back on by a professional.\n\n
        • Have an electrician check the electrical system and appliances.\n\n
        • Wells should be pumped out and the water tested for purity before drinking.\n\n
        Your home is no longer a safe place.\n\n
        • Throw away medicine, food, or water that had contact with floodwaters (including canned goods).\n\n
        • If water is of questionable purity, boil drinking water for 10 minutes.\n\n
        • Restrict children from playing in flooded areas.\n\n
        • Keep windows and doors open for ventilation.\n\n
        • Pump out flooded basements gradually (removing about 1/3 of the water volume each day) to avoid structural
        damage.\n\n
        • Keep the power off until an electrician has inspected the system for safety. All electrical equipment should
        be checked and dried before being returned to service.\n\n
        • Clean and disinfect everything that got wet.\n\n
        • Service damaged sewage systems as soon as possible.\n\n
        When making repairs, protect your property from future flood damage.\n\n
        • Follow local building codes.\n\n
        • Use flood-resistant materials and techniques.\n\n
        • Elevate electrical components above the potential flood height.\n\n
        • Elevate utilities (washer, dryer, furnace, and water heater) above the level of anticipated flooding.\n\n
        • Consider elevation of the entire structure.\n\n
        • Install a backflow valve in the sewer system.\n\n
    </string>

    // ##### Water

    <string name="swater_h">-: Water :-</string>
    <string name="swater_t1">\n

        \n\nPrepare an Emergency Water Supply
        \n\n
        \n\n Store at least 1 gallon of water per day for each person and each pet. Consider storing more water than
        this for hot climates, for pregnant women, and for people who are sick.
        \n\n Store at least a 3-day supply of water for each person and each pet. Try to store a 2-week supply if
        possible.
        \n\n Observe the expiration date for store-bought water; replace other stored water every 6 months.
        \n\n Store a bottle of unscented liquid household chlorine bleach to disinfect your water and to use for general
        cleaning and sanitizing. Try to store bleach in an area where the average temperature stays around 70°F (21°C).
        Because the amount of active chlorine in bleach decreases over time due to normal decay, consider replacing the
        bottle each year.
        \n\n

        \n\nWater Containers (Cleaning and Storage)
        \n\n
        \n\nUnopened commercially bottled water is the safest and most reliable emergency water supply.
        \n\n
        \n\nUse of food-grade water storage containers, such as those found at surplus or camping supply stores, is
        recommended if you prepare stored water yourself.
        \n\n
        \n\nBefore filling with safe water, use these steps to clean and sanitize storage containers:
        \n\n
        \n\n Wash the storage container with dishwashing soap and water and rinse completely with clean water.
        \n\n Sanitize the container by adding a solution made by mixing 1 teaspoon of unscented liquid household
        chlorine bleach in one quart of water.
        \n\n Cover the container and shake it well so that the sanitizing bleach solution touches all inside surfaces of
        the container.
        \n\n Wait at least 30 seconds and then pour the sanitizing solution out of the container.
        \n\n Let the empty sanitized container air-dry before use OR rinse the empty container with clean, safe water
        that already is available.
        \n\n
        \n\nAvoid using the following containers to store safe water:
        \n\n
        \n\n Containers that cannot be sealed tightly
        \n\n Containers that can break, such as glass bottles
        \n\n Containers that have ever held toxic solid or liquid chemicals, such as bleach or pesticides
        \n\n Plastic or cardboard bottles, jugs, and containers used for milk or fruit juices
        \n\n
        \n\nFor proper water storage:
        \n\n
        \n\n Label container as “drinking water” and include storage date.
        \n\n Replace stored water that is not commercially bottled every six months.
        \n\n Keep stored water in a place with a fairly constant cool temperature.
        \n\n Do not store water containers in direct sunlight.
        \n\n Do not store water containers in areas where toxic substances such as gasoline or pesticides are present.
        \n\n

    </string>

    // ##### Wild Fire

    <string name="swildfire_h">-: Wild Fire :-</string>
    <string name="swildfire_t1">
        \nBefore a Fire
        \n\n• Make digital copies of valuable documents and records like birth certificates.
        \n\n• Sleep with your door closed.
        \n\n• Contact your local fire department for information on training on the proper use and maintenance of fire
        extinguishers.
        \n\n• Consider installing an automatic fire sprinkler system in your residence.
        \n\n• A working smoke alarm significantly increases your chances of surviving a deadly home fire.
        \n\n• Create and Practice a Fire Escape Plan
        \n\n• A smoke alarm significantly increases your chances of surviving a deadly home fire.


        \n\nDuring Wild Fire
        \n\nStay informed
        \n\nPay attention to local weather forecasts, especially those that may affect fire conditions, and always
        listen to instructions given by local emergency management officials.
        \n\nProtect Yourself from Smoke
        \n\nTake steps to protect your health if your community is affected by smoke. Try to limit your time outdoors
        and practice safe driving. Be aware of smoke on roads because it could decrease visibility. Learn more about how
        you can protect your health and be safe if you are exposed to wildfire smoke.
        \n\nEvacuate Safely
        \n\n
        \n\nYou may be asked by public authorities to evacuate or you may decide to evacuate. Read about how to evacuate
        safely and how to develop a family disaster plan, including:
        \n\n• Finding out what could happen to you
        \n\n• Making a disaster plan
        \n\n• Completing the checklist
        \n\n• Practicing your plan
        \n\nStay Healthy During Power Outages
        \n\nLarge fires can cause long-term power outages. Read about what to do if your power goes out, including:
        \n\n• Preventing carbon monoxide poisoning
        \n\n• Food safety
        \n\n• Safe drinking water
        \n\n• Power line hazards


        \n\nAfter Wild Fire
        \n\nProtect Your Physical Well-Being

        \n\n• Drive safely: Be alert for broken traffic lights and missing street signs. Watch out for trash and debris
        on the road.
        \n\n• Be careful around damaged buildings or structures: Wait to return to buildings during daylight hours, when
        it is easier to avoid hazards, especially if the electricity is off and you have no lights.
        \n\n• Cleanup Safely: Wear proper safety equipment, avoid carbon monoxide poisoning, and avoid electrical
        hazards.
        \n\nProtect Your Emotional Well-Being
        \n\nAfter a disaster, such as a wildfire, you may feel sad, mad, guilty, or numb. You may have trouble sleeping,
        be constantly watching for danger, or be jumpy, irritable, or angry. Contact with certain people, sights, or
        sounds may bring back bad memories or an overwhelming sense of grief. These are all normal reactions to stress,
        as this is a difficult time. Here are some things you can do to help you cope with stress and protect your
        emotional and physical well-being:
        \n\n• Stay Active. Volunteer for work in a shelter, community, school, or faith-based organization.
        \n\n• Help with cleanup and repair if it is safe to do so.
        \n\n• Spend time with others.
        \n\n• Participate in activities you enjoy.
        \n\n• Take breaks from the cleanup efforts.
        \n\n• Exercise (indoors if air quality is not acceptable).
        \n\n• Keep a journal.
        \n\n• Talk about your feelings.
        \n\nKeep in mind that returning to the way you felt before the disaster may take time. Talk to a psychologist,
        social worker, or professional counselor if you are having trouble with the following:
        \n\n• Managing your feelings
        \n\n• Completing daily tasks
        \n\n• Caring for your family
    </string>

    // Drought

    <string name="adrought_h">-: Drought :-</string>
    <string name="adrought_t1">
        \n\nNearly every part of our country experiences periods of reduced rainfall. If we plan for drought, then we
        can enjoy the benefits of normal or rainy years and not get caught unprepared in dry years.
        \n\nBefore a Drought
        \n\nStrategies for drought preparedness focus mainly on water conservation. Make these practices a part of your
        daily life and help preserve this essential resource.
        \n\nIndoor Water Conservation Tips Prior to a Drought
        \n\nGENERAL
        \n\n * Never pour water down the drain when there may be another use for it. For example, use it to water your
        indoor plants or garden.
        \n\n * Repair dripping faucets by replacing washers. One drop per second wastes 2,700 gallons of water per year.
        \n\n * Check all plumbing for leaks and have any leaks repaired by a plumber.
        \n\n * Retrofit all household faucets by installing aerators with flow restrictors.
        \n\n * Install an instant hot water heater on your sink.
        \n\n * Insulate your water pipes to reduce heat loss and prevent them from breaking.
        \n\n * Install a water-softening system only when the minerals in the water would damage your pipes. Turn the
        softener off while on vacation.
        \n\n * Choose appliances that are more energy and water efficient.
        \n\nBATHROOM
        \n\n * Consider purchasing a low-volume toilet that uses less than half the water of older models. Note: In many
        areas, low-volume units are required by law.
        \n\n * Install a toilet displacement device to cut down on the amount of water needed to flush. Place a
        one-gallon plastic jug of water into the tank to displace toilet flow (do not use a brick, it may dissolve and
        loose pieces may cause damage to the internal parts). Be sure installation does not interfere with the operating
        parts.
        \n\n * Replace your showerhead with an ultra-low-flow version.
        \n\nKITCHEN
        \n\n * Start a compost pile as an alternate method of disposing of food waste or simply dispose of food in the
        garbage. (Kitchen sink disposals require a lot of water to operate properly).
        \n\nOutdoor Water Conservation Tips Prior to a Drought
        \n\nGENERAL
        \n\n * Check your well pump periodically. If the automatic pump turns on and off while water is not being used,
        you have a leak.
        \n\n * Plant native and/or drought-tolerant grasses, ground covers, shrubs, and trees. Once established, plants
        adapted to your local climate do not need water as frequently and usually will survive a dry period without
        watering. Small plants require less water to become established. Group plants together based on similar water
        needs.
        \n\n * Install irrigation devices that are the most water efficient for each use, such as micro and drip
        irrigation, and soaker hoses.
        \n\n * Use mulch to retain moisture in the soil. Mulch also helps control weeds that compete with landscape
        plants for water.
        \n\n * Avoid purchasing recreational water toys that require a constant stream of water.
        \n\n * Avoid installing ornamental water features (such as fountains) unless they use re-circulated water.
        \n\n * Consider rainwater harvesting where practical.
        \n\n * Contact your local water provider for information and assistance.
        \n\nLAWN CARE
        \n\n * Position sprinklers so water lands on the lawn and shrubs and not on paved areas.
        \n\n * Repair sprinklers that spray a fine mist. Most misting issues result from a pressure problem, properly
        regulating pressure in an irrigation system will prevent misting.
        \n\n * Check sprinkler systems and timing devices regularly to be sure they operate properly.
        \n\n * Raise the lawn mower blade to at least three inches or to its highest level. A higher cut encourages
        grass roots to grow deeper, shades the root system, and holds soil moisture.
        \n\n * Plant drought-resistant lawn seed. Reduce or eliminate lawn areas that are not used frequently.
        \n\n * Avoid over-fertilizing your lawn. Applying fertilizer increases the need for water. Apply fertilizers
        that contain slow-release, water-insoluble forms of nitrogen.
        \n\n * Choose a water-efficient irrigation system such as drip irrigation for your trees, shrubs, and flowers.
        \n\n * Turn irrigation down in fall and off in winter. Water manually in winter only if needed.
        \n\n * Put a layer of mulch around trees and plants to reduce evaporation and keep the soil cool. Organic mulch
        also improves the soil and prevents weeds.
        \n\n * Invest in a weather-based irrigation controller—or a smart controller. These devices will automatically
        adjust the watering time and frequency based on soil moisture, rain, wind, and evaporation and transpiration
        rates. Check with your local water agency to see if there is a rebate available for the purchase of a smart
        controller.
        \n\nPOOL
        \n\n * Install a new water-saving pool filter. A single back flushing with a traditional filter uses 180 to 250
        gallons of water.
        \n\n * Cover pools and spas to reduce evaporation of water.
        \n\nDuring a Drought
        \n\nAlways observe state and local restrictions on water use during a drought. If restricted, for example, do
        not water your lawn, wash your car, or other non-essential uses, to help ensure there is enough water for
        essential uses. Contact your state or local government for current information and suggestions.
        \n\nIndoor Water Conservation Tips While in a Drought
        \n\nBATHROOM
        \n\n * Avoid flushing the toilet unnecessarily. Dispose of tissues, insects, and other similar waste in the
        trash rather than the toilet.
        \n\n * Avoid taking baths—take short showers—turn on water only to get wet and lather and then again to rinse
        off.
        \n\n * Avoid letting the water run while brushing your teeth, washing your face or shaving.
        \n\n * Place a bucket in the shower to catch excess water for watering plants.
        \n\nKITCHEN
        \n\n * Operate automatic dishwashers only when they are fully loaded. Use the "light wash" feature, if
        available, to use less water.
        \n\n * Hand wash dishes by filling two containers—one with soapy water and the other with rinse water containing
        a small amount of chlorine bleach.
        \n\n * Clean vegetables in a pan filled with water rather than running water from the tap.
        \n\n * Store drinking water in the refrigerator. Do not let the tap run while you are waiting for water to cool.
        \n\n * Avoid wasting water waiting for it to get hot. Capture it for other uses such as plant watering or heat
        it on the stove or in a microwave.
        \n\n * Avoid rinsing dishes before placing them in the dishwasher; just remove large particles of food. (Most
        dishwashers can clean soiled dishes very well, so dishes do not have to be rinsed before washing)
        \n\n * Avoid using running water to thaw meat or other frozen foods. Defrost food overnight in the refrigerator
        or use the defrost setting on your microwave oven.
        \n\nLAUNDRY
        \n\n * Operate automatic clothes washers only when they are fully loaded or set the water level for the size of
        your load.
        \n\nOutdoor Water Conservation Tips While in a Drought
        \n\nCAR WASHING
        \n\n * Use a commercial car wash that recycles water.
        \n\n * If you wash your own car, use a shut-off nozzle that can be adjusted down to a fine spray on your hose.
        \n\nLAWN CARE
        \n\n * Avoid over watering your lawn and water only when needed:
        \n\n * A heavy rain eliminates the need for watering for up to two weeks. Most of the year, lawns only need one
        inch of water per week.
        \n\n * Check the soil moisture levels with a soil probe, spade or large screwdriver. You do not need to water if
        the soil is still moist. If your grass springs back when you step on it, it does not need water yet.
        \n\n * If your lawn does require watering, do so early in the morning or later in the evening, when temperatures
        are cooler.
        \n\n * Check your sprinkler system frequently and adjust sprinklers so only your lawn is watered and not the
        house, sidewalk, or street.
        \n\n * Water in several short sessions rather than one long one, in order for your lawn to better absorb
        moisture and avoid runoff.
        \n\n * Use a broom or blower instead of a hose to clean leaves and other debris from your driveway or sidewalk.
        \n\n * Avoid leaving sprinklers or hoses unattended. A garden hose can pour out 600 gallons or more in only a
        few hours.
        \n\n * In extreme drought, allow lawns to die in favor of preserving trees and large shrubs.
        \n\n

    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_live_updates">LiveUpdates</string>
    <string name="tab_text_1">Tab 1</string>
    <string name="tab_text_2">Tab 2</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main_map">Map</string>

</resources>
